So today we will talk about budget friendly health
insurance plans.  What are these budget-
friendly health insurance plans
?  Many times it happens that you go to
buy health insurance and you feel that it is
beyond your budget.  Its premium
is very high or you go for adequate cover.
Adequate cover means that you
feel that this much cover should be there according to my future
, according to health inflation.
But its premium is very
high.  Today we will talk about
how you can get budget friendly health insurance.
So stay till the end of the video.  This is going to be a
very useful video.
[Music]
Quick reminder before starting the video,
if you haven't subscribed to our channel yet, do so so that you get
the right
information at the right time, like now
you will get budget friendly health insurance.
Basically you want your
insurance cover to be high, 50 lakh, 60 lakh,
₹1 crore, but you also want to pay less premium.  If
you want to adequately insure yourself and at the
same time
want to pay less premium, then what is the solution for that
?  This is his session.  We have one base
health insurance policy and one super
top up health insurance policy.  Base cover is
what you initially buy to
cover yourself and has all the
comprehensive features you need.  There is
no room rent capping.  There are no sublimits.
Consumables are covered.   There
is comprehensive coverage.  Modern
treatments are fully covered.  So that's what a base
cover is.  Super Topup basically became
more popular during the time of Covid.
In 2020, people were getting high bills
and people were not adequately insured.  So
he wanted to give himself more cover at a lower premium.
So that is called Super
Topper Plan.  How does Super Topper Plan work
?  They work on top of your base health insurance.
You take a base cover
and a super top-up along with it.  So the
base will have a premium.  Super Topup will have
a premium.  There is a concept called deductible in Super Topup.  This
means that the
super top-up will work on that deductible.  There is a base
and a super top-up.  It's over.
After that it will work.  So the deductible is
basically the annual aggregate deductible.   Let us
understand with an example.  You have taken a base policy for
₹5 and a super top up for
₹95, which costs very little.
We will see further.  If the first claim comes from LETS for ₹3
lakh, then it will be covered by a policy of ₹5 lakh.   The
second claim came for ₹5 lakh.  Now only
₹ lakh is left in your base policy because the
base policy was of ₹ 5 lakh.  Now that cover will be
replenished.  Next year when you
renew.  Only two are left now.  So two will
come from the base policy and three from the super top-
up insurance.  After that a
claim of Rs 10 lakh came.  Where will I get it now
?  From Super Top Up Insurance Policy
because the threshold of Rs 5 lakh which was
deductible for Super Top Up has been completed.  On
top of that, the Super Top Up policy
is now activated and will work the same way for the entire year.
So you can claim up to Rs 95 lakh through Super Topup.
So your base and super
top up can be any amount.
Deductible super top-up may also vary.
Depending on your base cover.  The
idea is to
take the same amount of deductible in super top-up as the premium you are already paying for the base.  Suppose if
your base cover is Rs 10 lakh then the super top up should be Rs 90 lakh.
If you are targeting 1 crore
then you are targeting less, let's say if you are
targeting 50 then it should be 40.  So
10 + 40 makes it 50 but it is
not a straight forward 50.
This will start only after this policy ends.  And this should
happen in the same cycle.  Meaning, if the contract is for one year, then
try to
take both the policies at the same time.  So that you can
use the base and super topup together.
And now the premium of Super Topper policy will
always be low because the base policy is a very
comprehensive policy.
You may have to compromise on something in Super Topper.
Let's say on the room sub limits
consumables which are non-payable items may
not be covered but your family is
getting some protection.  Getting a cover.
A backup is available which is the Super Top Up
plan which is offering higher sum assured
at a lower price.  Let's see, here I have
compared some five companies on super top
up and base.  So let's talk about premiums once.
Here the family size taken is
family of four.  Edge Lee is 35, 32, 5 and
two.  I have a family of four and for them
I have tried to make a combination of base and super top up
so that they are
adequately covered and the premium is also
reduced.  So here I have taken EVP Rush 2.0 Bronze
Plus which is a slightly economical plan.
You all know the features.  Detailed
videos of all these products are also available
on our channel.  We will
also put all the detailed videos in its description box.  I will
post their links.  You
can refer.  But here I am talking about the concept.
So there is a premium for Reash 2.0 Bronze Plus over Lemon.
Here I will
share with you both Zone One and Zone Two premiums.
Zone One is Delhi, NCR, Mumbai,
some parts of Gujarat.  Everyone else falls into Zone Two or
Zone Three.  So here we will
talk about the premiums of Zone One and Zone Two,
where you live, you pay the premium accordingly.
So in Zone One's Neema Bhupa
ReShored 2.0 Bronze Plus, if you
take the base sum assured, the Zone One premium is ₹
17.94 for a family of four.  Policy of Rs 10 lakh for
four people.  The premium is coming to
₹1,904.  I have not added any add-ons here.
And if you take it from Zone Two,
your premium is approximately 10% less.
Which is ₹1.91.
Now here we have taken the base of 5.   On
top of that we have to take super top up.
Generally, the premium for Super Topup remains the same.  There is
no difference according to your zone.  So premium of Rs. 95
with deductible of Rs. 5.  Meaning, after exhausting 5 lakhs, he can
use 95 lacs.  Its
premium is Rs 5857 for an year.  So you
understand that if you are in Zone One then 17,000 + 5857
which will be covered by 5 + 95.  If you are in zone two then
15,000 + 5857 which is 5 + 95 will cover you.
Now if you take sum assured 10 lax
base.  Ok?  And
what happens if you take a super top-up of ₹90?
So, for a base of 10 lakhs, the premium for Zone One
is ₹20,000 (20649), and for Zone Two it is ₹
17381.  Again there is a difference of around 10%.
And the premium for Super Topup will now be Rs
90 instead of Rs 95 with a deductible of Rs 10.  Now if
we increase the deductible then the premium of
super top-up will reduce.  The premium became
₹1531.
So you'll see this when you're taking bases
from zone one, 17,000 + 6000, you're
getting base cover for about 23,000.  23 Base
plus Super Topper 5 + 95 for 24000 When you are taking 10 + 90
then 20000 + 1500 means
you are getting only 1 crore in 22-23000 but 10 + 90
then second option is better because
you are getting more base cover which has
comprehensive coverage.  So 10 + 90 will
always work as a better combination.  That's why
I have kept both combinations.  So that
you can see and 10 and Y not five.  So
with five you get 95.  10 plus 90 will give you 90.
Now let's talk about HDFC Aego Optima
Secure, if the base sum assured is 5 lakh, the
premium from zone one is 26000, for zone two it is
21000, the super topup will cost 4400, so
here the super topup is available for a maximum of 20 lakhs
only, whose deductible is 5 lakhs
maximum, so there are more options for super topup,
otherwise even if you are taking 5 + 20, it will
make 25 or if you are taking 10 + 20,
there also you will have to
take deductible of 5 only, so 5 + 20 which is 25 will cost
you 26 + 4400,
approximately 31000 and if you take 10 + 20,
then the cost is around 35000, from zone one for
zone two it is a little less.  Then let's talk about
Aditya Birla Activ 1, which
is the base plan and also comes with a super top-up.
Aditya Birla Active One Max, which
is the base plan, has a sum assured of Rs 5 lakh and
is currently not available.  I think starts with minimum intake.
But I have taken it for you with 10.
If we take the base of Rs 10, the
premium for Zone One is Rs 21,000 and the
premium for Zone Two is Rs 17,000 which is more than
10% difference.  There is a difference of approximately 15%.  And the
premium of Super Topup is Rs 90 lakh, your
premium comes to Rs 4,948.  Then come
ICICI Lo LBA Daily Weight Pay.  Let's see 10 +
90 here also.  The base premium of 10 is Rs
17,000 for Zone One and Rs 15,000
for Zone Two.  And on top of that, a super
top up of 90 lacs is Rs 3,700.  This means you are
getting a cover of Rs 1 crore for Rs 20,000 for a family of
four which is very good.  So we
should focus on more cover so that if any
disease occurs tomorrow, it does not happen that you have to
withdraw money from your savings.  Then
we have taken Manipal Cigna Sarawaha Plan, the
best plan.  The premium there for 5 lakhs is
₹23,000 and if you take it from zone two
then it will be ₹18,000. A
cover of 30 lakhs is available with 5 lakhs deductible in super top up that is
₹6100.  If
we increase the deductible of this, that is, we
take the base of Rs 10 and take the deductible of Rs 10 along with Rs 30,
then the situation becomes even better.
Meaning if you were getting 30 LE with your 5 LE
i.e. ₹35 LE you were paying
around ₹30 in above combinations 5 + 30 and
10 + 30 then ₹000 is your base
premium of zone one and ₹1000 is the premium of zone two.
You have a super top-up of Rs 1820.
So for ₹26,000 + 1800 i.e. approximately ₹28,000, you are
getting more coverage of 10 + 30 i.e. 40 lakhs.  The premium also has to be paid less.
So ideally, in the situation,
if you take a super top up with Rs
10 deductible, it will be very economical
and your purpose of
providing more cover to your family and providing cover at a lower premium will be
solved.  So you
can see some add ons in the base policy
which are mandatory add ons which I
think are riders, that is your cover for on payable
items.  You can add cover for consumable items.
Provides protection
Provides fully comprehensive protection
for base cover.  If the option is also available in Super Topup in ICICI.
You can add on non-payable items.
In all other plans, your non-payable items are
not covered in Super Topup.  So this is what I
wanted to tell you,
how to plan your health insurance budget?  Because
you want to take health insurance and
we all know that Rs 5 lakh, Rs 10 lakh will
not be of any use in the future.  We actually
need time assurance of crores.  So to
get sum assured of crores, we will have to plan
smartly.  So if you
want more cover at a lower premium then
this is the option and this is the hack that you
can use for your family.  If you have
already taken the base policy, review it.  Add a top-up
policy immediately and from the same company
so that you do not face any issues at the time of claims.
Because you will have to serve waiting periods in top-up also.
If you are
taking a new policy then add it today.   Do
n't wait.  If you want to understand the features of all these plans,
base, super top-up, then we will
put them below.  You can refer
whatever plan you want to explore.
And if you want guidance and
want to connect with our team, you
can WhatsApp on the given number
and fill the Google form.  Our
team will connect you.
Quick reminder before we go, if you have
n't subscribed to our channel yet, do so.
So that you get the right information at the right
time.  See you in the next video.   Till then
stay safe.  Take care.  Bye-bye.
Om